<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantum Entanglement - PC5132 Project Website</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/</link><description>Recent content on Quantum Entanglement - PC5132 Project Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 21:43:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>History</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/history/</guid><description>History # Following the declaration by Max Born that quantum mechanics is probabilistic in nature in 1926, Albert Einstein famously criticized the theory by saying “God does not play dice”. Niels Bohr, who supported the theory, reportedly told Einstein to &amp;ldquo;stop telling God what to do&amp;rdquo;. The debate between Einstein and Bohr continued for about 8 years, before Einstein formulated his best argument against Bohr’s theory: the EPR (Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen) paradox.</description></item><item><title>Preliminaries</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/preliminaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/preliminaries/</guid><description>Preliminaries # Before we start, we would like to introduce a few concepts that will be needed later.
Uncertainty Principle # I am sure that your physics teachers have taught you this: when conducting physics experiments, the measurements you make must be accompanied by an “uncertainty”. Your teacher may have told you that this “uncertainty” value is due to the accuracy of the measuring instrument, as well as human error.</description></item><item><title>Dirac Notation</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/dirac-notation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/dirac-notation/</guid><description>Dirac Notation # Prerequisite: Basic Linear Algebra (covered under H2 ’A’ Level Further Mathematics Syllabus)
Dirac notation is often used in quantum mechanics and quantum information to describe phenomena. Here we will try to explain the notation that you will need to know.
Ket # A ket \(\vert\psi\rangle\) can be represented by a column vector.
For example, a 2 dimensional ket could be represented by \(\begin{pmatrix} v_1 \\ v_2 \end{pmatrix}\) , and a 3 dimensional ket could be represented by \(\begin{pmatrix} v_1 \\ v_2 \\ v_3 \end{pmatrix}\) , and so on (where \(v_i\in\mathbb{C}\) for \(i\in\mathbb{N}\) ).</description></item><item><title>Definition</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/definitions/</guid><description>Definition # Entanglement # Entanglement refers to a phenomenon observed in quantum systems where multiple particles in a system are unable to be described independently of one another.1
The term &amp;ldquo;entanglement&amp;rdquo; was introduced by Schrödinger in his 1935 article. 2 Entanglement exists between multiple particles. When performing an operation on one of the particles, the other entangled particles may also be affected by this operation.
In Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s paper, he also highlighted the unintuitiveness of quantum entanglement.</description></item><item><title>EPR Paradox and Bell's Theorem</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/epr-paradox-bell-theorem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/epr-paradox-bell-theorem/</guid><description>EPR Paradox # The EPR paradox is a thought experiment intended to demonstrate an inherent paradox in the early formulations of quantum theory. It was to counter an assumption in quantum physics. Niels Bohr and Werner Heisenberg said that a quantum particle or system does not have a definite value until a measurement takes place.
However, if we could predict with certainty the value of a physical quantity without in any way disturbing a system, then there exists an already given value corresponding to that quantity.</description></item><item><title>Applications</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/applications/</guid><description>Applications # We will be looking at certain applications of quantum entanglement. There are a few applications of quantum entanglement quantum cryptography, extremely precise clocks, quantum computers and improved microscopes.
Extremely precise clocks # Look at your watch, and the time on your computer or phone. Chances are they may not display the same time. Even if they do, either you have calibrated your watch to prevent having too big an error or your watch requires a change of battery.</description></item><item><title>Quiz</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/quiz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/content/quiz/</guid><description>Quiz # Now that you have gone through the website, heres a short quiz for you!
There are 6 Multiple Choice Questions in total. Read through all of the options carefully.
When you feel you have answered the questions confidently, click on the Answer box to reveal the correct answer.
Question 1 # When you perform an operation on one particle, how long does it take for the other entangled particle to be affected?</description></item><item><title>Distribution of Work</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/misc/distribution-of-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/misc/distribution-of-work/</guid><description>Distribution of work # Sik Feng # Dirac notation, Definition of entanglement Bell&amp;rsquo;s Theorem and CHSH game Website management Josiah # EPR paradox Applications of entanglement (quantum clocks, quantum computing, quantum cryptography) Yifan # Introduction History of quantum mechanics Preliminaries</description></item><item><title>Tools Used</title><link>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/misc/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sikfeng.github.io/pc5132-project/misc/tools/</guid><description>Tools used for developing this website # Hugo website hosted on Github Pages, using Hugo Book Theme Manim Community v0.11.0 for animations</description></item></channel></rss>